# **Zach Schnackel**

**UI/Motion Developer** 

P: 919.645.7123

@: zachschnackel@gmail.com



I'm a UI Engineer living in Charleston, SC. My background involves pushing the limits of what can be built on the backend, how we experience it on the frontend, and the project management that brings it all together. My passions are perfecting process and educating those around me.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### DigitalOcean

UI Engineer

JAN 2016 - CURRENT

Lead development efforts on creating an internal framework used to power the main website and ongoing brand initiatives.

Implemented style guides for saner development workflows. Work alongside a talented group dedicated to accessibility and performance.

### **BoomTown**

UI Engineer

JULY 2014 - DEC 2015

BoomTown is a real estate marketing and lead generation platform. I curated their entire frontend platform, by integrating a several CSS/JS components within a system that scales to multiple themes and millions of users each month. I worked with

Object Oriented JS frameworks like Backbone everyday.

#### Blue Ion

Developer

JAN 2013 - MAY 2014

Lead design, frontend and backend implementation updates across a vast array of clients and requirements. Was an integral part of client interactions and scoping project specifications.

### Yellow House Design

Developer

SEP 2008 - JAN 2013

Worked with various clients on implementing CMS based solutions and providing custom frontend/backend solutions. Was the lead developer in creating an online Moulding Catalog application that can scale to a multitude of clients and was used to startup a new subentity of the company.

# RECENT PROJECTS

#### Float

DO.CO/FLOAT

COMING SOON

A CSS/JS framework built to meet the needs of ongoing DigitalOcean brand initatives. Sass, PostCSS, ES6, and GSAP - > all these buzz-words and more! Coming to a repo near you.

### DigitalOcean

DO.CO

APR 2016 - AUG 2016

DigitalOcean is not only an evolving product, but also an ever-growing brand. The previous iteration had served its purpose for several years, but I lead architecture decisions and implementation for its new lick 'o paint!

#### Hactkoberfest

HACKTOBERFEST.DIGITALOCEAN.COM

SEP 2016 -OCT 2016

A month-long celebration of open-source and what we can do when we work together. I worked alongside some very talented folks to bring this year's version to life.

## **EDUCATION**

### Associates In Science

Wake Tech

2005